Guide to the Frederick W. Hilles Manuscript Collection and Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Frederick W. Hilles Manuscript Collection, 1645–1969; Series I; 17.94; 41 boxes + 1 broadside.
  - Literary and Historical Manuscripts, 1688–1951
    - West, Benjamin, 1814 July 25 (Box 18, Folder 561)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from London, 1 page. Accompanied by an engraving of West by Henry Meyer from a painting by Sir Thomas Lawrence.
    - West, Benjamin, 1816 June 4 (Box 18, Folder 562)
      Autograph letter, signed, to John Young, from Staines, 1 page.
    - Whittier, John Greenleaf, 1883 May 15 (Box 18, Folder 563)
      Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Danvers, Massachusetts, 4 pages.
    - Williams, John, 1791 February 18 (Box 18, Folder 564)
      Autograph letter, signed Anthony Pasquin, to Richard Phillips, 1 page.
    - Windham, William, circa 1807-1809; 1802–1814 (Box 19, Folder 565-566)
      Extracts from the diary of William Windham (1783-1791), with an introduction: two autograph manuscripts in an unidentified hand, circa 1807-1809. With typescripts
    - Woodfall, Henry Sampson, undated (Box 19, Folder 567)
      Autograph manuscript notes for the binding and repair of sixteen volumes.
    - Woollett, William, 1772–1785 (Box 19, Folder 568)
    - Wordsworth, William, 1835 March 30 (Box 19, Folder 569)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Henry T. Liddell, from Trinity Lodge, 3 pages.
    - Wraxall, Sir Nathaniel William, 1803 November 2 (Box 19, Folder 570)
    - Wright, John, 1834 (Box 19, Folder 571)
      Five autograph letters, signed, to George Crabbe.
    - Wyndham, Sir George O'Brien, 3rd Earl of Egremont, 1831–1837; undated (Box 19, Folder 572)
      Five autograph letters, signed, to Thomas Phillips. Accompanied by an engraving of Wyndham by H. Cook after a painting by Phillips.
    - Yeberrie?, Agnes, 1890 November 14 (Box 19, Folder 573)
      Autograph letter, signed, to "Evelyn," from Eastbourne, 2 pages.
    - Yonge, Charlotte Mary, 1880 November 3 (Box 19, Folder 574)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Duncan, from Winchester, 4 pages.
    - Yorke, Philip, Second Earl of Hardwicke, 1769 July 18 (Box 19, Folder 575)
      Autograph letter, signed, to David Garrick, 2 pages. Accompanied by an engraving of Hardwicke by Ridley from the painting by Romney.
    - Assorted bindings (Box 40, Folder 931-933)
      Bindings removed from unidentified works.
  - Carlyle Manuscripts, 1645–1911
    Organized under three headings: Writings, Correspondence, and Photographs.
    - Writings, 1841–1881
      - Carlyle, Jane Welsh, undated (Box 20, Folder 576)
        Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Chelsea, 2 pages.
      - Carlyle, Jane Welsh, undated (Box 20, Folder 577)
        Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Bingle, from Chelsea, 10 pages.
      - Carlyle, Jane Welsh, 1841 April 9, undated; 1841 April 9 (Box 20, Folder 578)
        Two autograph letters, signed, to Thomas Carlyle.
      - Carlyle, Jane Welsh, 1842 August 11 (Box 20, Folder 579)
        Letter, written in the hand of Mary Carlyle, to Thomas Carlyle, from Troston, 3 pages. Includes autograph manuscript notes by Thomas Carlyle.
      - Carlyle, Jane Welsh, 1857 (Box 20, Folder 580)
        Two autograph letters, signed, to Colonel Sir David Davidson, from Chelsea.
      - Carlyle, Jane Welsh, 1858 January 21 (Box 20, Folder 581)
        Autograph letter, signed, to George Eliot, from Chelsea, 7 pages.
      - Carlyle, Jane Welsh, 1866 March 23 (Box 20, Folder 582)
        Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Simpson, from Chelsea, 3 pages.
      - Carlyle, Jane Welsh, 1852 (Box 20, Folder 583)
        Two autograph letters, signed, to Penelope Sketchley.
      - Carlyle, Jane Welsh, ? November 6 (Box 20, Folder 584)
        Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Story, from Chelsea, 3 pages.
      - Carlyle, John Aitken, 1862 February 26 (Box 20, Folder 585)
        Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Stirling, from Edinburgh, 1 page.
      - Carlyle, John Aitken, 1848?; 1848 (Box 20, Folder 586)
        Autograph letter, signed, to John Welsh, from Chelsea, 3 pages.
      - Carlyle, Mary Carlyle (Aitken), 1875 February 8 (Box 20, Folder 587)
      - Carlyle, Mary Carlyle (Aitken), 1881 (Box 20, Folder 588)
        Two autograph letters, signed, to Sir Joseph Edgar Boehm.
      - Carlyle, Mary Carlyle (Aitken), 1881 February 6 (Box 20, Folder 589)
        Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Owen, from Chelsea, 2 pages. Includes a draft of a reply on page 4.
      - Carlyle, Mary Carlyle (Aitken), 1876 March 7 (Box 20, Folder 590)
        Autograph letter, signed, to John Ruskin, from Chelsea, 3 pages.
      - Carlyle, Thomas, undated (Box 20, Folder 591)
        Calling card with address at St. Leonards written in ink by Carlyle and admission ticket to the lectures on heroes and the heroic, signed and numbered by Carlyle.
      - Carlyle, Thomas, undated (Box 20, Folder 592)
        Autograph manuscript notes, in pencil and ink, written on the recto and verso of a printed announcement of a meeting of the London Library Committee, 1 leaf.
      - Carlyle, Thomas, undated (Box 20, Folder 593)
        Autograph manuscript fragment, containing part of a sentence, 1 leaf.
      - Carlyle, Thomas, undated (Box 20, Folder 594)
        Autograph manuscript list of book and periodicals, 1 leaf.
      - Carlyle, Thomas, 1860 November 1 (Box 20, Folder 595)
        Autograph manuscript quotation, signed, Chelsea, 1 page.
      - Carlyle, Thomas, 1866 March 27 (Box 20, Folder 596)
        Autograph note for admitting Dr. Hunter to the Rector's Installation Address at Edinburgh, April 2, 1 leaf.
      - Carlyle, Thomas, 1867 May 11 (Box 20, Folder 597)
        Autograph manuscript note in Latin, signed, Chelsea, 1 page.
      - Carlyle, Thomas, undated (Box 20, Folder 598)
        Autograph manuscript notes for Frederick the Great, 6 leaves.
      - Carlyle, Thomas, undated (Box 20, Folder 599)
        Autograph letters, signed, from John Sterling to Carlyle, with manuscript copies of several letters from Sterling to Carlyle with autograph manuscript annotations by Carlyle. Also includes autograph manuscript notes by Carlyle. 33 leaves.
      - Carlyle, Thomas, undated (Box 20, Folder 600)
        Life of John Sterling proof sheets, with autograph manuscript corrections by Carlyle, 2 leaves.
      - Carlyle, Thomas, undated (Box 20, Folder 601)
        Autograph manuscript note on Mirabeau for The French Revolution, 1 leaf.
      - Carlyle, Thomas, undated (Box 21, Folder 602)
        Phallus Worship autograph manuscript, 7 leaves.
      - Carlyle, Thomas, undated (Box 21, Folder 603)
        Reminiscences autograph manuscript fragment, partly in Carlyle's hand and partly in the hand of Mary Carlyle, with autograph manuscript corrections in Carlyle's hand, 5 leaves.
      - Carlyle, Thomas, 1867 (Box 21, Folder 604)
        Shooting Niagara: and After? autograph manuscript fragment of a draft of the article, written for Macmillan's Magazine for August 1867.
    - Correspondence, 1772–1911
      Organized under two headings: Outgoing and Incoming.
      - Outgoing, 1818–1911
        Arranged chronologically by recipient.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, undated (Box 21, Folder 605)
          Autograph letter to an unidentified recipient, 1 page.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, undated (Box 21, Folder 606)
          Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient. Accompanied by an engraving of Carlyle by T. Cole after a photograph by Julia Cameron.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, undated (Box 21, Folder 607)
        - Carlyle, Thomas, undated (Box 21, Folder 608)
        - Carlyle, Thomas, circa 1837?; 1832–1842 (Box 21, Folder 609)
          Autograph letter to an unidentified recipient, from Chelsea, 3 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1837 December 17 (Box 21, Folder 610)
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1841 February 25 (Box 21, Folder 611)
          Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Chelsea, 3 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1842 January 30 (Box 21, Folder 612)
          Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, Chelsea, 1 page.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1842 June 17 (Box 21, Folder 613)
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1843 April 13 (Box 21, Folder 614)
          Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Chelsea, 1 page.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1844 April 20 (Box 21, Folder 615)
          Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, Chelsea, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1844 September 5 (Box 21, Folder 616)
          Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Chelsea, 3 pages. "F. Locker" is written in ink on page 4.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1845 January 8 (Box 21, Folder 617)
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1845 May 12 (Box 21, Folder 618)
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1846 May 17 (Box 21, Folder 619)
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1846 July 6 (Box 21, Folder 620)
          Autograph letter, signed with initials, to "The Printer," from London, 1 page.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1847 January 7 (Box 21, Folder 621)
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1847 August 7 (Box 21, Folder 622)
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1848 February 3 (Box 21, Folder 623)
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1849 May 1 (Box 21, Folder 624)
          Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Chelsea, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1852 December 9 (Box 21, Folder 625)
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1856 October 2 (Box 21, Folder 626)
          Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, Scotsbrig, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1856 October 7 (Box 21, Folder 627)
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1857 March 23 (Box 21, Folder 628)
          Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Chelsea, 2 pages. Includes a manuscript note in an unidentified hand on page 4.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, circa 1858?; 1853–1863 (Box 21, Folder 629)
          Fragment of an autograph letter to an unidentified recipient, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1859 March 14 (Box 21, Folder 630)
          Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from Chelsea, 3 pages. The closing and signature have been supplied from another letter and have text on the verso.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1859 October 8 (Box 21, Folder 631)
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1860 May 25 (Box 21, Folder 632)
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1863 February 9 (Box 21, Folder 633)
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1864 June 19 (Box 21, Folder 634)
          Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from St. Leonards, 1 page.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1864 July 3 (Box 21, Folder 635)
          Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, from St. Leonards, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1867 November 21 (Box 21, Folder 636)
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1869 April 12 (Box 21, Folder 637)
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1872 April 22 (Box 21, Folder 638)
          Letter, written in an unidentified hand, to an unidentified recipient, from Chelsea, 1 page.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1873 May 5 (Box 21, Folder 639)
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1878 December 9 (Box 21, Folder 640)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Berthold Auerbach, from Chelsea, 2 pages. Accompanied by an autograph letter, signed, from Auerbach to Carlyle, 1 page.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1826 December 27 (Box 21, Folder 641)
          Autograph letter, signed, to John Badams, from Edinburgh, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1855 June 7 (Box 21, Folder 642)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Ballantyne, from Chelsea, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1842 December 31 (Box 21, Folder 643)
          Autograph letter, signed, to James Ballantine, from Chelsea, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1848 September 26 (Box 21, Folder 644)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Ballantyne, from the Grange, Alresford, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1848 May 14 (Box 21, Folder 645)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Juliette Baner, from Chelsea, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1844 (Box 21, Folder 646)
          Two autograph letters, signed, to Harriet Baring, Lady Ashburton.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1874 May 18 (Box 21, Folder 647)
          Manuscript letter, written in the hand of an amanuensis, to Sir Joseph Edgar Boehm, from Chelsea, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1845 June 7 (Box 21, Folder 648)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Booth, from Chelsea, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1862 October 21 (Box 21, Folder 649)
          Autograph letter, signed, to V. Botta, from Chelsea, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1831 July 11 (Box 21, Folder 650)
          Autograph letter, signed, to John Bowring, from Craigenputtock, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1859 May 5 (Box 21, Folder 651)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Ford Madox Brown, from Chelsea, 3 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1841 July 29 (Box 21, Folder 652)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Robert Browning, from Newly, Annan, N.B., 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1851 October 10 (Box 21, Folder 653)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Robert Browning, from Chelsea, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1851 October 28 (Box 21, Folder 654)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Robert Browning, from Chelsea, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1868 March 26 (Box 21, Folder 655)
          Autograph letter, signed, to A. N. Buckheim, from Chelsea, 1 page.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1849 July 4 (Box 21, Folder 656)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Jane Welsh Carlyle, from Dublin, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1861–1863 (Box 21, Folder 657)
          Two autograph letters, signed, to John Aitken Carlyle, from Chelsea.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1842 August 1 (Box 21, Folder 658)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Sir Edwin Chadwick, from Chelsea, 3 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1843 June 13 (Box 21, Folder 659)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Chapman and Hall, from Chelsea, 1 page. Accompanied by Carlyle's calling card, with an autograph manuscript note, signed.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1845 April 25 (Box 21, Folder 660)
          Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, possibly Chapman and Hall, from Chelsea, 3 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1845–1846 (Box 21, Folder 661)
          Two autograph letters, signed, to Chapman and Hall.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1847 November 25 (Box 21, Folder 662)
          Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, possibly Chapman and Hall, from Chelsea, 1 page.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1850 October 10 (Box 21, Folder 663)
          Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, possibly J. C. Cochrane, from the Grange, Alresford, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1840 (Box 21, Folder 664)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Henry Cole, 1 page.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1837 Spring?; 1837 (Box 21, Folder 665)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Crawfurd, from Chelsea, 1 page.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1849 September 29 (Box 21, Folder 666)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Aubrey De Vere, from Chelsea, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1857 May 17 (Box 21, Folder 667)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Lady Devonshire, from Chelsea, 3 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1867 January 24; undated (Box 21, Folder 668)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Miss Dickens, from Mentone, France, 1 page. Pasted to a framed photograph of Carlyle by the firm of Elliott & Fry, with "John Lothrop Motley" written on the back of the frame. Accompanied by three additional photographs of Carlyle by Elliott & Fry and an engraving of Carlyle by J. C. Armytage after the portrait by Samuel Lawrence.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1852 July 12 (Box 21, Folder 669)
          Autograph letter, signed, to George A. Dods, from Chelsea, 1 page.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1838 December 17 (Box 21, Folder 670)
          Autograph letter, signed, to J. W. Donaldson, from Chelsea, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1855 September 17 (Box 21, Folder 671)
          Autograph letter, signed, to an unidentified recipient, possibly W. B. Donne, from Chelsea, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1864 October 17 (Box 22, Folder 672)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Robert Farie, from Chelsea, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1856 October 18 (Box 22, Folder 673)
          Autograph letter, signed, to "Fitzgerald," from Chelsea, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1849 February 21 (Box 22, Folder 674)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Frewen, from Chelsea, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1848–1850 (Box 22, Folder 675)
          Two autograph letters, signed, to John Forster.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1856 May 12; undated (Box 22, Folder 676)
          Two autograph letters, signed, to Alexander Gilchrist.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1835–1844 (Box 22, Folder 677)
          Two autograph letters, signed, to Mr. Grant, from Chelsea.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1846–1847 (Box 22, Folder 678)
          Autograph letter, signed, and a manuscript copy of a letter to John Grey, from Chelsea.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1855 July 10 (Box 22, Folder 679)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Grote, from Chelsea, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1853 January 28 (Box 22, Folder 680)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Sir George Grove, from Chelsea, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1843 May 4 (Box 22, Folder 681)
          Autograph letter, signed, to "Jenny" Janet Carlyle Hanning, from Chelsea, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1868 February 14 (Box 22, Folder 682)
          Autograph letter, signed, to "Jenny" Janet Carlyle Hanning, from Chelsea, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1849 March 26 (Box 22, Folder 683)
          Autograph letter, signed, to the Reverend John Hope, from Chelsea, 1 page. A manuscript note in an unidentified hand about Hope is present on the verso.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1863 March 18 (Box 22, Folder 684)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Alexander Ireland, from Chelsea, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1846 December 22 (Box 22, Folder 685)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Geraldine Jewsbury, from Chelsea, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1863 August 31 (Box 22, Folder 686)
          Autograph letter, signed, to J. E. Jones, from the Grange, Alresford, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1850 October 31 (Box 22, Folder 687)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Charles Kingsley, from Chelsea, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1869 February 13 (Box 22, Folder 688)
          Autograph letter, signed, to G. W. Kitchin, from Mentone, France, 1 page.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1841 May 14 (Box 22, Folder 689)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Sir George Cornewall Lewis, from Chelsea, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1860 October 10 (Box 22, Folder 690)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Sir George Cornewall Lewis?, from Chelsea, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1855 May 17 (Box 22, Folder 691)
          Autograph letter, signed, to "Miss Lowe," from Chelsea, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1860 February 26 (Box 22, Folder 692)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Sir Stephen Lushington, from Chelsea, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1865 May 17 (Box 22, Folder 693)
          Autograph letter, signed, to William Maccall, from Chelsea, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1870 October 17 (Box 22, Folder 694)
          Letter, signed, in the hand of Mary Aitken Carlyle, to William Maccall, from Chelsea, 3 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1845 August 5 (Box 22, Folder 695)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. Mackenzie, from Chelsea, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1853 March 13 (Box 22, Folder 696)
          Autograph letter, signed, to James Mackenzie, from Chelsea, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1841 December 24 (Box 22, Folder 697)
          Autograph letter, signed, to William Charles Macready, from Chelsea, 3 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1843 February 1 (Box 22, Folder 698)
          Autograph letter, signed, to James Marshall, from Chelsea, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1858 November 1 (Box 22, Folder 699)
          Autograph letter, signed with initials, to John Menzies, from Chelsea, 1 page.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1839 December 31 (Box 22, Folder 700)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Richard Monckton Milnes, First Baron Houghton, from Chelsea, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1818 July 28; 1823 June 17 (Box 22, Folder 701)
          Two autograph letters, signed, to Thomas Murray.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1854 December 16 (Box 22, Folder 702)
          Autograph letter, signed, to John Nichol, from Chelsea, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1862 September 15 (Box 22, Folder 703)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Sir Richard Owen, from Chelsea, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1867 May 28 (Box 22, Folder 704)
          Autograph letter, signed, to the editor of the Pall Mall Gazette, from Chelsea, 1 page.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1849 May 12 (Box 22, Folder 705)
          Autograph letter, signed, to J. W. Parker, from Chelsea, 2 pages. Page 3 includes an autograph manuscript note, signed "R. G."
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1858 November 9 (Box 22, Folder 706)
          Autograph letter, signed, to J. W. Parker, from Chelsea, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1852 November 12 (Box 22, Folder 707)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Remington, from Chelsea, 3 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1840–1850; undated (Box 22, Folder 708)
          Ten autograph letters, signed, to Mrs. Rich.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1845 September 18 (Box 22, Folder 709)
          Autograph letter, signed, to R. Richmond, from Chelsea, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1844 February 28 (Box 22, Folder 710)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Miss Rigby, from Chelsea, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1847 May 16 (Box 22, Folder 711)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Robertson, from Chelsea, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1850 April 11 (Box 22, Folder 712)
          Autograph letter, signed, to the Reverend E. Rudge, from Chelsea, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1869 August 3 (Box 22, Folder 713)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Katherine Louisa Russell, Lady Amberley, from Chelsea, 1 page.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1854 January 6 (Box 22, Folder 714)
          Autograph letter, signed, to A. R. Scoble, from Chelsea, 1 page.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, undated (Box 22, Folder 715)
          Two autograph letters, signed, to James or Thomas Spedding, from Chelsea.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1842 November 18 (Box 22, Folder 716)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Stephen Edmund Spring-Rice, from Chelsea, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1854 (Box 22, Folder 717)
          Two autograph letters, signed, to Stephen Edmund Spring-Rice, from Chelsea.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1867 July 1 (Box 22, Folder 718)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Miss Stanley, from Chelsea, 1 page.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1843 May 10 (Box 22, Folder 719)
          Autograph letter, signed, to John Steill, from Chelsea, 3 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1865 August 1 (Box 22, Folder 720)
          Autograph letter, signed, to C. Stewart, from Scotsbrig, 2 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1844 December 22 (Box 22, Folder 721)
          Autograph letter, signed, to Miss Stirling, from Chelsea, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1857 September 13 (Box 22, Folder 722)
          Autograph letter, signed, to John Strachey, from Chelsea, 4 pages.
        - Carlyle, Thomas, 1848 November 28 (Box 22, Folder 723)
          Autograph letter, signed, to J. C. Symons, from Chelsea, 4 pages.